three things I like about the element 26
hybrid leather weightlifting belt or the
pairing of leather and nylon the
self-locking Buckle plus the stability
it provides me during my lifts I've been
using this belt for a couple of months
now so why don't we go ahead and dig
into my findings
[Music]
what's good everybody it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym with another
review locked and loaded for y'all this
time I've got the element 26 hybrid
leather weight lifting belt in this
video I'm going to tell you everything
you need to know about this belt from
the price and the features as well as
the pros and the cons and who should or
maybe should not toss this in their gym
bag but before I get going with all that
I gotta let you know we've reviewed a
lot of weightlifting belts on barbin.com
and if you want to browse our best list
just go ahead and search bar Bend best
weight lifting belt you can find out for
yourself which one takes home that
number one spot
okay so what do I like about the element
26 hybrid leather weightlifting Bill
well for starters let's talk about
stability that's huge for your workouts
can be very beneficial for your gains
and I have to say I definitely feel more
supported as I'm going to do a heavy
squat or a deadlift the pairing of
leather nylon makes this a really
versatile belt in my opinion and I think
you can use it for all styles of
workouts whether that be powerlifting
Olympic or CrossFit style workouts think
you can do it all the self-locking
Buckle makes it super easy to get in and
out of the belt in between your sets or
your exercises and plus it's pretty
comfortable and I think we all can
appreciate that
foreign
[Music]
with this weight lifting belt let's talk
about the thickness first some people
you know if you're really lifting super
heavy you might want a thicker belt than
this one right here that's the case I'd
probably suggest going for a fully
leather belt the self-locking Buckle
here I like it makes it really easy to
put it on take it off but it might not
be as secure as a belt that features a
lever and lastly it's not tapered
meaning it's the same width all the way
around and that could be a bit of a
problem for some people as they go to do
a deadlift for example because it might
make it a little bit more difficult to
reach over and grab your barbell
[Applause]
all right now when it comes to price you
can find the element 26 hybrid leather
weightlifting belt right around 60 bucks
on the element 26 website you can also
purchase it on Amazon if you prefer
doing that now considering this does
have a leather build I think it's a
pretty solid value a lot of fully
leather belts are way more expensive
they can be around 150 bucks and since
this is more versatile in my opinion
than a strictly leather belt I think
it's gonna be worth the money because
you could use it for any style workout
that you may be doing
foreign
okay so let's talk about the build now
and some of the features you'll find
with the element 26 hybrid leather
weight lifting belt so for starters you
do have a hybrid build with leather and
nylon provides you with a lot of
stability during your lifts but it's
also pretty comfortable a little
versatile at the same time so you can
use it for you know more athletic I
guess exercises than just your typical
big three of you know squat bench and a
deadlift now you do have a steel Buckle
right here this is a quick release
Buckle self-locking super easy to get in
and out of it you also have a pairing of
a velcro strap it's going to add even
more security as you go to lock this
belt around your belly button this belt
is not tapered as I previously mentioned
so you have a uniform four inch wide
profile all the way around could be a
bit of an issue for some people as they
go to reach over and grab their barbell
for a deadlift and whenever you measure
yourself for this belt you want to
measure around your belly button because
that's where you're going to be placing
it not around your hips so keep that in
mind you also have five different sizes
available for you to purchase so the
extra small is going to range from 23 to
27 inches the small is going to be from
27 to 31 inches the medium is 31 to 36
inches the largest 36 to 40 inches and
that extra large is 40 to 45 inches
around your belly button
all right y'all let's go and do a quick
walk around with the element 26 hybrid
leather weight lifting belt once again I
have the medium and whenever you go to
size yourself for your specific belt you
want to do so around your belly button
because well that's where the belt's
going to be not around your waist your
hips like you know a normal belt is so
anyways you do have that steel Buckle
right here it's a self locking buckle
you know it's gonna be really easy to
take this on and off you pair that up
with this velcro right here it's going
to keep everything nice and secure for
you all right so I'm gonna show you guys
you know just how to use this belt
really fast so
rip that velcro you want to split these
two rollers right here and make sure
this belt comes all the way out
[Music]
now whenever you go to put it on you
know once again you want this around
your belly button so go ahead and get it
positioned where you want
go ahead and take this strap run it
through
split these two rollers right here
guide it in there and then from there
you know once again just make sure
everything's lined up and then pull it
tight as far as you want it to go it's
going to be nice and secure and give you
that nice stability for your workouts
foreign
[Music]
okay so who should purchase the element
26 hybrid leather weightlifting belt
well if you are in fact in the market
for a new belt that can be used for
power lifting Olympic style lifting or
even CrossFit definitely think you'll
want to take a hard look at this belt
right here because it can handle all
those workouts if you're looking for a
belt that provides both stability and
comfort you know I definitely think this
checks off both of those characteristics
and the self-locking Buckle is going to
be great for anybody who wants to put
the belt on or take it off quickly in
between their exercises
[Music]
all right so what about the people who
might not want to purchase this
weightlifting belt well let's talk about
the thickness first and foremost it
might not be as thick as a fully leather
belt so it might not provide as much
stability for some people and if that's
the case you know I'd definitely suggest
it's going to find a fully leather belt
because of the uniform design right here
it's not tapered in the front so it
could be you know a bit of a hassle for
some people as they're going to do their
deadlifts for example as I've mentioned
that a couple of times and while I
really do like the self-locking Buckle
it's pretty easy to put it on or take it
off quickly but at the same time it
might not be as secure as a belt that
features a lever so if you know that's
something you're worried about you want
that little extra security blanket you
might want to go and find a belt that
does have a lever all right well that's
a wrap on today's review over the
element 26 hybrid leather weight lifting
belt I personally love this thing
provides me with both stability and
comfort during my workouts I think power
lifters can use it I think crossfitters
can use it this is a really versatile
belt but you know once again it's not
tapered in the front you do have that
uniform width right here that could be a
little bit annoying for some people and
also you know it might not provide as
much support as a fully leather belt can
thanks for watching everybody I hope
this video was really helpful and I was
able to answer any questions you may
have about this weightlifting belt as
always stay tuned for my next review but
for now you should absolutely head over
to barbin.com and read more about this
product right here just search barbend
element 26 hybrid leather weightlifting
belt review you'll find everything I
talked about here today I'll see y'all
next time
foreign
[Music]